Finding aid for the Henry Clay Frick Papers, Series II: Correspondence, 1882-1929, undated HCFF.1.2
The Frick Collection/Frick Art Reference Library Archives
Henry Clay Frick Papers, Series II: Correspondence
1882-1929, undated
HCFF.1.2
The Frick Collection/Frick Art Reference Library Archives
39.4 Linear feet (95 boxes)
Henry Clay Frick (1849-1919), a Pittsburgh industrialist who made his fortune in coke and steel, was also a prominent art collector. This series consists largely of Frick's incoming correspondence, with some outgoing letters, on matters relating to business and investments, art collecting, political activities, real estate, philanthropy, and family matters.
Frick, Henry Clay, 1849-1919.
Provenance
On deposit from the Helen Clay Frick Foundation, 2001.
Access Restrictions
These records are open for research under the conditions of The Frick Collection/Frick Art Reference Library Archives access policy. Contact the Archives Department for further information at archives@frick.org.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically. Items are nearly always filed under the name of the correspondent (last name first, in the case of personal names; corporate bodies are filed in direct order). In a handful of cases, materials are filed by subject.
Scope and Content
Henry Clay Frick's Correspondence series (1882-1929, and undated) consists chiefly of incoming letters, including circular letters, telegrams, statements, reports, memoranda, and notes, as well as enclosures and related material. In some cases, copies of Frick's outgoing responses are also included. Items in this series are arranged alphabetically, either by the last name of the correspondent, or by the name of the firm, organization, or publication (e.g. Chas. D. Barney and Co., Seamen's Church Institute, Princeton University,Scottdale Observer, etc.) In a handful of instances, materials are filed by subject (e.g. La Sarraz, Switzerland; painter Andrea del Sarto, etc.) Topics discussed in Frick's correspondence vary widely, and include business dealings, investments, art collecting, philanthropy, politics, real estate, and family matters.
The earliest items in this series date from 1882, and include correspondence with Andrew Carnegie and the distillery A. Overholt & Co. From the 1880s through the 1910s, though, Frick corresponded with a wide array of industrialists, bankers, investment firms, executives, and managers, and was a frequent correspondent with members of the Phipps, Mellon, Morgan, and Rockefeller families. Frick's principal business activities were in the areas of coal and coke, iron, steel, and railroads. Materials pertaining to these concerns may be found either under the name of the corporate entity or under the names of individual executives. For instance, in addition to the correspondence filed under Carnegie Steel Co., additional letters can be found under Andrew Carnegie, Millard Hunsiker, A.L. Griffin, J. Ogden Hoffman, F.T.F. Lovejoy, H.M. Curry, and John C. Fleming. Similarly, H.C. Frick Coke Co. correspondence also appears under the names Thomas Lynch, Robert Ramsay, and W.C. Magee. Other executives in the coke, steel, and railroad industries with whom Frick corresponded include Jay C. Morse, W.L. Brown, W.H. Donner, Elbert H. Gary, J.W. Gates, E.B. Leinsenring, Samuel Mather, George W. Perkins, Morris Ramsay, Josiah V. Thompson, and A.R. Whitney, as well as Alexander J. Cassatt, Samuel Rea, William H. Joyce, James McCrea, and John S. Wilson, all of the Pennsylvania Railroad. Examples of industrialists and bankers associated with Frick are Henry G. Morse, Carl C. Law, F.W. Haskell, S.L. Schoonmaker, H.C. McEldowney, and E.B. Morris. Also documented in this series are Frick's investments at various brokerage houses, largely through statements and transactional correspondence with firms such as Lee, Kretschmar and Co., Boissevain and Co., Charles Smith and Sons, James D. Smith and Co., and Kuhn, Loeb and Co.
Letters to Frick on the subject of art collecting range from offers of paintings and other objects available for purchase, to requests to visit Frick's gallery, to transactional correspondence regarding the purchase, framing, conservation, insurance and transport of paintings. Such letters are filed under the names of his principal art dealers, M. Knoedler and Co. and Charles Carstairs, as well as under Duveen Brothers, through whom Frick made acquisitions from J.P. Morgan's estate among other purchases, Roger Fry, who assisted Frick in the acquisition of Rembrandt's Polish Rider and also alerted Frick to the availability of other works, and Arthur Tooth & Son, through whom Frick purchased his first old master painting. Additional correspondents who wrote about acquisitions or possible acquisitions include Alice Creelman, Virginia P. Bacon, James H. Dunn, H. Silva White, Julius Oehme, and Jacques Seligmann, among numerous others. An index of works offered to Frick in these files is available, and additional art correspondence can be found in the Henry Clay Frick Papers, Series I: Art Files and in the Henry Clay Frick Art Collection Files in this repository.
Correspondence on philanthropic matters documents Frick's contributions to museums and other cultural institutions, colleges and universities, hospitals, churches, and civic organizations. These include the Metropolitan Museum of Art, Boston Museum of Fine Arts, American Museum of Natural History, the American Academy in Rome, Harvard University and its Arnold Arboretum, Princeton University, from which Frick's son Childs graduated in 1905, and Columbia University. Materials may be filed under the name of the institution, but can also appear under the names of officials and administrators, as in the case of John Grier Hibben of Princeton University, and Nicholas M. Butler of Columbia University. Notable civic organizations in receipt of Frick's assistance were the Pittsburgh Newsboys' Home, Pittsburgh Association for the Improvement of the Poor, Kingsley House Association, and the Henry Clay Frick Educational Commission, founded by Frick in 1909 with the assistance of Pittsburgh astronomer John Brashear.
In addition to his interests in business and art, Frick's papers also document his political activities. Though he himself never held office, he was a strong supporter of the Republican Party, and took an interest in both national politics and those in Pennsylvania, where he maintained legal residency and returned to cast his ballot annually. Frick had prominent political connections, as evidenced by correspondence with Senators Boies Penrose, M.S. Quay, and Philander Chase Knox (later a cabinet member to Presidents Roosevelt and Taft), Representative Edward E. Robbins, and Judge Joseph Buffington, Roosevelt's Treasury Secretary, Leslie M. Shaw, and Roosevelt's personal White House secretary, William Loeb, Jr. Frick's correspondence contains letters to and/or from all U.S. Presidents from Harrison through Wilson, though in some instances there is only a letter or two. The bulk of Frick's presidential correspondence is with Theodore Roosevelt, through whom Frick donated a painting to the White House in 1903. Topics discussed in Frick's political correspondence include campaign contributions, nominations and appointments, and the political climate of the time. Local politics and civic matters are also discussed, especially in the letters of H.D.W. English, Frank F. Nicola, and Pittsburgh mayor William A. Magee.
Frick's correspondence concerning real estate details the acquisition, improvement, and administration of property, whether for the family's personal use, or for commercial, industrial, or rental purposes. Of note is his correspondence with various architects of the period, including F.J. Osterling and F.E. Alden, who undertook projects at the Frick residence in Pittsburgh; Little & Browne, who designed the Frick house in Prides Crossing, Mass.; Thomas Hastings, architect of the Frick family's New York residence; Daniel Burnham, who designed the Frick Building in downtown Pittsburgh as well as the Frick monument in Homewood Cemetery; and Hunt & Hunt, who made alterations to the Vanderbilt mansion in New York during the time of the Frick family's residency there. Files of letters to and from George Lockhart Allen, a real estate and insurance broker based in Salem, Mass., document the acquisition of land for Frick's Prides Crossing estate, relations with his neighbors, and the social climate of the area at that time. Another correspondent of note, D.B. Kinch, was at times responsible for the administration of the Frick Building in Pittsburgh, and superintending the construction of the Frick residence in New York.
These letters sometimes give insight into Frick's personal interests and hobbies, especially those items documenting his memberships in various sporting, social, and fraternal organizations, as well as in correspondence with C.L. Charley, a Parisian auto dealer who imported cars for Frick, and the naval architectural firm of Tams, Lemoine and Crane, through whom he chartered a yacht just after the turn of the century. These papers also document aspects of Frick's private life and the operation of his office and household through correspondence with his immediate family (his wife Adelaide, son Childs, and daughter Helen Clay), members of the extended Frick, Childs, and Overholt families, employees at his various residences, and office staff in New York and Pittsburgh.
Biographical Note
Henry Clay Frick (1849-1919) was a prominent industrialist and art collector who made his fortune in the coal, coke, steel, and railroad industries. Born into modest circumstances in West Overton, Pa., Frick ended his formal education by the mid-1860s. In 1871, he borrowed money to purchase a share in a coking concern that would eventually become the H.C. Frick Coke Co. Over the next decade, he continued to expand his business through the acquisition of more coal lands and coke ovens, and entered into partnership with fellow industrialist Andrew Carnegie in 1882. Frick assumed the chairmanship of Carnegie Bros. & Co. (later Carnegie Steel Co.) in 1889, and served in that capacity until his resignation from the company in December 1899. During his tenure as chairman, differences between Frick and Carnegie emerged, most significantly in their approach to labor issues. The 1892 Homestead Strike further strained relations between the two men, and in 1899, Frick permanently severed his relationship with Carnegie.
In December 1881, Frick married Adelaide Howard Childs of Pittsburgh. The couple purchased a house (called Clayton) in Pittsburgh's East End, and had four children: Childs Frick (1883-1965), Martha Howard Frick (1885-1891), Helen Clay Frick (1888-1984), and Henry Clay Frick, Jr. (born 1892; died in infancy). After his break with Carnegie in 1899, Frick began spending less time in Pittsburgh. In 1905, he leased on the Vanderbilt mansion at 640 Fifth Avenue in New York City, and built an elaborate summer residence (Eagle Rock) on Boston's North Shore, which was completed in 1906. Though Frick maintained his status as a Pittsburgh resident for the remainder of his life, he and his family chiefly divided their time between Massachusetts and New York. In 1907, Frick purchased land at the corner of Fifth Avenue and 70th Street in New York City. Construction of the new Frick residence, designed by Thomas Hastings of the firm Carrère and Hastings, began in 1912, after the demolition of the Lenox Library formerly on the site. The family moved into the house at One East 70th Street in the fall of 1914, and Henry Clay Frick died there on 2 December 1919.
Frick showed a lifelong interest in art collecting, acquiring his first painting in 1881, and continuing to add to his collection until just before his death. Little is known about Frick's early experiences with art, but his taste initially favored local Pennsylvania artists, contemporary French painters, and Barbizon landscapes. Around the turn of the century his focus shifted to old master paintings, and he began to collect works by Rembrandt, Vermeer, Van Dyck, and Gainsborough. In the mid-1910s, Frick greatly expanded his collection by acquiring paintings, porcelains, sculpture, enamels, and furnishings from the estate of J.P. Morgan, who had died in 1913. Though Frick acquired paintings from a variety of sources, his primary dealer was M. Knoedler & Co., and two principals of that firm, Charles Carstairs and Roland Knoedler, were friends of Henry Clay Frick in addition to helping him build his collection. Upon his death, Frick bequeathed to the public his New York residence, along with the paintings, furnishings, and decorative objects contained therein. The Frick Collection opened to the public in 1935.
Allom, Charles, Sir, 1865-1947.; Arthur Tooth & Sons.; Burnham, Daniel Hudson, 1846-1912.; Carnegie Steel Company.; Carnegie, Andrew, 1835-1919.; Carrère & Hastings.; Carstairs, Charles.; Creelman, Alice.; De Wolfe, Elsie, 1865-1950.; Duveen Brothers.; Frick, Adelaide Howard Childs, 1859-1931.; Frick, Childs, 1883-1965.; Frick, Helen Clay, 1888-1984.; Frick, Henry Clay, 1849-1919.; Fry, Roger Eliot, 1866-1934.; H.C. Frick Coke Company.; Hastings, Thomas, 1860-1929.; Knox, Philander C. (Philander Chase), 1853-1921.; M. Knoedler & Co.; Osterling, F. J., 1865-1934.; Penrose, Boies, 1860-1921.; Quay, Matthew Stanley, 1833-1904.; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison), 1874-1960.; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919.; Art dealers.; Art--Private collections.; Coal mines and mining.; Correspondence.; Industrialists--United States.; Mansions--New York (State)--New York.; Presidents--United States--Correspondence.; Railroads--History.; Steel industry and trade.
- A.A. Parker - A.N. Marquis (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  A.A. Parker and Bro. (Detroit, Mich.), 1885-1902
  A. Dodge and Son Corp. (Beverly, Mass.), 1914
  A.E. Masten and Co. (Pittsburgh, Pa.), 1915
  A.E. Osler and Co. (Toronto, Can.), 1919
  A.E. Thiede and Co. (Chicago, Ill.), 1911
  A.F. Parsons Publishing Co. (New York, N.Y.), 1893
  A.G. Spalding Bros. (Chicopee Falls, Mass.), 1897
  A.H. Kinkaid and Co. (Chicago, Ill.), 1903
  A. Iselin and Co. [New York, N.Y.?], 1907
  A.J. Woodruff and Co. (New York, N.Y.), 1907
  A. Kimbel and Sons (New York, N.Y.), 1892
  A.N. Marquis and Co. (Chicago, Ill.), 1919
- A. Overholt - A. Warner (Box 1, Folder 2)
  A. Overholt and Co. (Pittsburgh, Pa.), 1882-1919
  A.W. and R.B. Mellon (Pittsburgh, Pa.), 1920
  A.W. McLaughlin and Co. (New York, N.Y.), 1915
  A. Warner and Co. (Chicago, Ill.), 1889
- Abbott - Acklen (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Abbott, Gordon, 1903, 1911
  Abbott, Holker, 1911
  Abbott, Lyman, 1898
  Abbott, William L., 1888-1892
  Aberdeen and Temair, Marquess of, 1916-1917
  Ablett, J., 1893
  Abrams, Alfred W., 1909-1910
  Abt, Valentine, 1897-1908
  Academy of Arts and Letters (New York, N.Y.), 1909
  Academy of Our Lady of Mercy [Pittsburgh, Pa.?], 1900
  Academy of Science and Art (Pittsburgh, Pa.), 1890
  Acetylene Gas Illuminating Co. (New York, N.Y.), 1901, 1903
  Acheson, Ernest F., 1913
  Ackerman, Geo. W., 1908
  Ackermann, Harry B., 1910
  Acklen, J.H., 1914
- Adair - Adams, John Quincy (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Adair, Henry I., 1900
  Adair, James, 1895, 1909
  Adam, Paul, 1904
  Adams, Allie C., 1896
  Adams, C.C., 1898
  Adams, Edith Lucile, 1916
  Adams, Edward D., 1910-1919
  Adams, Frank C., 1895
  Adams, G.B.C., 1895
  Adams, H.S., 1919
  Adams, Henry Clay, Mrs., 1914
  Adams, Henry H., 1896-1903
  Adams, Herbert K., 1909
  Adams, J.Q., 1905
  Adams, John Quincy, 1917
- Adams, L.E.- Aetna (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Adams, L.E., 1893
  Adams Express Company (New York, N.Y. ), 1905, 1916
  Adams Express Company (Pittsburgh, Pa.), 1913
  Adams, Livingston and Davis (New York, N.Y.), 1913
  Adamson, Robert, 1913
  Addenbrook, Thomas, 1894, 1903
  Addington Golf Syndicate Limited (London, England), 1919-1925
  Aeolian Company (New York, N.Y.), 1906-1918
  Aetna Sand and Gravel Co. [no place], 1906
- Agassiz - Albery (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Agassiz, Rudolf, 1908-1910
  Agatha, S[iste]r. M., 1894
  Agnew, Lockett, 1916
  Aishton, R.H., 1917-1919
  Akron Trust Company [Akron, Ohio], 1902
  Alan, Hebert and Greening, Ltd. (London, England), 1913
  Albany Burgesses Corps (Albany, N.Y.), 1909
  Albery, F.F.D., 1913
- Alden, E.H., 1906-1920 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Alden, F.E. - Alexander, J.F. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Alden, F.E., 1896-1897
  Alden and Harlow, Architects (Pittsburgh, Pa.), 1897, 1899
  Aldis, Owen, 1901
  Aldred, J.E., 1910
  Aldrich, Nelson W., 1900, 1909
  Alexander and Colby (New York, N.Y.), 1902-1903
  Alexander and Green (New York, N.Y.) - See: C.B. Alexander
  Alexander and Steiner (Augusta, Ga.), 1910
  Alexander Brown and Sons (Baltimore, Md.), 1906
  Alexander, C.B., 1902
  Alexander, Charles E., 1906
  Alexander, Grace Green (Mrs. H.A. Alexander), 1908
  Alexander Hamilton National Memorial Association, [no place], 1909
  Alexander, Harriet F. (Mrs. C.B. Alexander), 1909, 1917
  Alexander, J.F., 1905-1910
- Alexander, J.S. - Algonquin (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Alexander, J.S., 1917
  Alexander, James W., 1903-1904
  Alexander, Jas. W., 1904
  Alexander, John S., 1910
  Alexander, John W., 1913, 1915
  Alexander, Leo, 1900
  Alexander, Maitland, 1905-1915
  Alexander, W., 1894
  Alexander, William, 1905
  Alexander, William A., 1917
  Alfred Higbie and Company (Washington, D.C.), 1917
  Algeo Brother Real Estate Agency (Allegheny, Pa.), 1889
  Alger, Philip R., 1894
  Algonquin Club (Boston, Mass.), 1894
- Allan A. Ryan - Allan, Bryce (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Allan A. Ryan and Co. (New York, N.Y), 1919
  Allan, Anna (Mrs. Bryce J. Allan), [1913-1914], 1917
  Allan, Bryce J., 1907-1917
- Allan, Bryce J., 1918-1920 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Allan Line - Allen, Allegheny (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Allan Line of Royal Mail Steamships, 1893
  Alldred, J., 1886
  Allegheny Country Club, 1909
  Allegheny County Commissioner's Office (Pittsburgh, Pa.), 1902
  Allegheny County Light Co., 1896-1897
  Allegheny County Sabbath School Association, 1906
  Allegheny General Hospital, 1903, 1908
  Allegheny Union Fresh Air Mercy Mission, 1900
- Allen, George Lockhart, 1902-1910 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Allen, George Lockhart (continued), 1911-1919 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Allen, Halle - Allison (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Allen, Halle and Co. (New York, N.Y.), 1905
  Allen, Harold, 1916
  Allen, J. Scott, 1910
  Allen, James Lane, 1915
  Allen, Janet, 1896
  Allen, Jennie L.C., 1895-1896
  Allen, John A. - See: Pullman Palace Car Porters and Railway Employees Beneficial Association
  Allen, Wm. H., 1886
  Allen, William H. - See: Bureau of Municipal Research
  Allerton House Company [New York, N.Y.?], 1922
  Allewelt, D.B., 1903
  Allgood, Jno. E., 1897
  Alliance Française, Comité de Pittsburgh (Pittsburgh, Pa.), 1908-1920
  Allied Theatrical and Motion Picture Team (New York, N.Y.), 1918
  Allies Hospitals Relief Commission (New York, N.Y.), 1916
  Allison, Chas. J., 1895, 1898
  Allison, Wm. M., Jr., 1904
- Allom, Charles C., 1914-1919 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Almy - American Academy in Rome (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Almy, W.F., 1897
  Alpern, Louis, 1916
  Alsop, E.B., 1913
  Altemus Mfg. Co. - See: Lyman B. Childs
  Alten, Geo., Mrs., 1897
  Altman, Benjamin, 1911-1912
  Alvord, Horace, 1902
  Amalgamated Copper Company (New York, N.Y.), 1900-1901, 1915
  American Academy in Rome (New York, N.Y.), 1906-1917
- American Academy of Arts and Letters - American Artists' (Box 2, Folder 5)
  American Academy of Arts and Letters (New York, N.Y.), 1916
  American Academy of Political and Social Science (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1903-1908
  American Art Annual(New York, N.Y.), 1906, 1916
  American Art Association (New York, N.Y.), 1913
  American Artists' Committee of One Hundred (New York, N.Y.), 1917
- American Bank - American Bond (Box 2, Folder 6)
  American Bank Note Company (New York, N.Y.), 1891-1913
  American Bond and Mortgage Co. (Chicago, Ill.), 1909
- American Chamber - American Consul (Box 2, Folder 7)
  American Chamber of Commerce in Paris (Paris, France), 1907-1914
  American Civic Alliance (New York, N.Y.), 1909-1910
  American Coal and Railway Company (New York, N.Y.), 1905
  American Committee for Training in Suitable Trades the Maimed Soldiers of France - See: Louis Baylies
  American Consul (Thomas R. Wallace) [no place], 1913
- American Express Co. [various locations], 1902-1917 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- American Federation - American Iron (Box 2, Folder 9)
  American Federation of Arts (Washington, D.C.), 1915
  American Geographical Society (New York, N.Y.), 1919
  American Golfer, Inc. [no place], 1909-1919
  American Home Watchmen (Pittsburgh, Pa.), 1917
  American Immigration and Distribution League (New York, N.Y.), 1914
  American Institute of Architects (Pittsburgh, Pa.), 1898, 1907
  American Institute of Mining Engineers (New York, N.Y.), 1903, 1918-1919
  American International Corporation (New York, N.Y.), 1916-1918
  American Iron and Steel Association (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1908
  American Iron and Steel Institute (New York, N.Y.), 1913, 1919
- American League - American Red (Box 2, Folder 10)
  American League for World Peace by Allied Victory (New York, N.Y.), 1918
  American Loan and Trust Company (Boston, Mass.), 1906
  American Locomotive Company (New York, N.Y.), 1902
  American Mailing Device Corporation (New York, N.Y.), 1919
  American Manufacturer and Iron World(Pittsburgh, Pa.), 1893, 1897
  American Museum of Natural History (New York, N.Y), 1903-1919
  American Museum of Safety (New York, N.Y), 1911
  American National Bank of Barberton (Barberton, Ohio), 1901, 1904
  American Protective Tariff League (New York, N.Y.) - See: Edward H. Ammidown
  American Red Cross [various locations], 1909-1910, 1918
- American Sheet - American Vanadium (Box 2, Folder 11)
  American Sheet and Tin Plate Company (Pittsburgh, Pa.), 1919
  American Ship Building Company (Cleveland, Ohio), 1899-1902
  American Social Hygiene Association, Inc. (New York, N.Y.), 1915, 1920
  American Specialty Co. (New York, N.Y.), 1901
  American Steel and Wire Co. (Pittsburgh, Pa.), 1905-1911
  American Surety Company of New York [various locations], 1885, 1917-1924
  American Telephone and Telegraph Co. (New York, N.Y.), 1910, 1912
  American Tinned Plate Association (Pittsburgh, Pa.), 1889
  American Trust Company (Boston, Mass.), 1910
  American Tube and Iron Co. (Middletown, Pa.), 1892
  American Vanadium Co., [no place], 1914
- Americus - Amster (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Americus Republican Club (Pittsburgh, Pa.), 1892-1916
  Amerine, M.H., 1894
  Ames, Elva L., 1919
  Ames Implement and Seed Company (Boston, Mass.), 1916
  Ammidown, Edward H., 1890
  Amory, Harcourt, 1905
  Amster, N.L., 1919
- Andel - Angus (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Andel, Coleman E., 1915
  Anderson, A.E., 1894
  Anderson, Alice T., 1900
  Anderson, C.F., 1899
  Anderson, DuPuy and Co. (Pittsburgh, Pa.), 1897
  Anderson, Geo. H., 1896-1901
  Anderson, Henry B., 1905
  Anderson, Peirce, 1911
  Anderson, R.M., 1913
  Anderson, S.H., 1900
  Anderson, T. Hart, 1909
  Andreini, J.M., 1908
  Andreoni, Orazio, 1893
  Andrew, Edwin, 1916
  Andrew, William W., 1917
  Andrews, B.B., 1916
  Andrews, Horace E., 1915
  Andrews, Samuel, 1905, 1909
  Andrews, W.C., 1893-1894
  Andrews, William, 1903
  Andrews, William H., 1890
  Anema, R., 1915
  Angell, L.E., 1890
  Angelo, Peter, 1892-1893
  Angle, J.E., 1919
  Anglo-American Savings and Loan Association (New York, N.Y.), 1893
  Anglo-American Telegraph Co. (New York, N.Y.), 1910
  Angus, G.W.R., 1911
- Anonymous, 1913-1915 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Re: working conditions in Frick's Pittsburgh office
- Anson - Antisell (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Anson, Alfred, 1914-1919
  Anthoney, [?], 1923
  Antisell, E., 1909
- Apgar - Armstrong (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Apgar, Robert R., 1919
  Applebaugh, C.E., 1905
  Applegate, C.H., 1900